what is a real blessing what is the view
this sometimes people ask well I guess you
sometimes people ask well I guess you
can define it a blessing is something
that's gonna it's gonna be beneficial
for your well-being in the future that's
just off the top of my head to define
blessing so if you take that as a
criteria then then you can see that
actually fundamentally you are the only
one who's responsible for your own
blessings you can't have somebody bless
you well you can have somebody bless you if
well you can have somebody bless you if
somebody comes and tells you what to do
properly accurately in terms of the mind
development in terms of the virtuous
life and and that kind of inner growth
yeah that person is sort of giving you
blessings ie
he's basically giving you opportunity to
bless yourself but most often people
just resort to blessings as a form of
superstition which is the sole point of
it is to cover up the existential
anxiety fear of basically life because
you recognize that you are nothing you
are alive you're bound with the life
your family your attachments you want
you to desires with everything but deep
down you know you're not in control of
it at any second it can be taken away so
that recognition it's dreadful
so a person without any wisdom without
an instruction or guidance would
basically have to turn towards
distracting himself from it but sooner
or later it starts to catch up and
that's when people become religious
superstitious engage in all sorts of
rituals and blessings and needs just do
Tamar to cover up so that Murad will be
fine because you recognize that further
you're not in control right here and now
and if your future is uncertain
you might not live next moment but
blessings being pertaining to your
well-being in the future you feel
blessed now you sort of smooth
the anxieties of the future so you
basically brings you some sort of peace
but it's it's not it's not a it's not
actually peace that kind of fixes the
problem it's the peace that comes from
ignoring the problem which is no really
your self may keep in the acts of virtue
upholding the virtue opposing the no
ill-will non-centrality non hatred non
slander wrong speech inciting violence
anything basically unwholesome non
indulgence you can you can be rest sort
of assured that there is a that is a
relatively universally accepted blissful
behavior it will it will result in your
in the future well-being and that's what
it's meant when the you know like with
the five precepts we spoke before they
would say like the Buddha would say it
would it would provide you with
confidence and you have nothing to fear
because you know with these criterias
they are not holding strictly or
virtuous behavior no ill-will non
indulgence and so on you start
recognizing it good as they are and then
you see yeah this would most certainly
be good for me even in the future so you
have confidence upon it so then you
don't have anxiety right all right
because why because you're not not means
behavior you have no you're not giving
in for anything unwholesome so you feel
protected with your own actions and you
can't ask for higher blessing than that
if the blessings will truly depend upon
somebody else which means you will
always be at the mercy of someone else's
will which would bring you back to the
nature or anxiety as it is right now or
you are not in control you're at the
mercy of elements circumstances
accidents and whatnot you're in murcia
something else so if you want real
blessing is the blessing that you can
make a difference you can sort of have
an input in and that's the blessing that
I'm talking about of a virtuous behavior
and there is no nobody in between there
so nobody can take a credit away nor can
you blame anybody else if you don't
it's on you exactly